## Ou Changkun

Curriculum Vitae

Science and art, life in between

changkun.de 🔇

©changkun (7

Frauenlobstr. 7a 80337 Munich, Germany

**\** +49 157 7214 1480 / +86 186 1322 5636

➤ changkun.ou@ifi.lmu.de / hi@changkun.us

Born on October 25th 1993 in Zhijiang/Hunan/China

People's Republic of China citizenship

Single

Last update: May 13, 2019

### Introduction

Changkun Ou is a research assistant at the University of Munich. His research topics are interdisciplinary in computational geometry, imitation learning, and human-computer interaction. In particular, he would like to leverage three-dimensional polygonal mesh representation learning and visual preference elicitation to develop efficient algorithms or industrial tools for 3D modeling and rendering.

#### Education

University of Munich (LMU)  **Research Assistant*	Munich, Germany Feb. 2019 – Present
University of Munich  Master of Science in Human-Computer Interaction; GPA: 1.63/1.00	Munich, Germany Oct. 2016 – Jan. 2019
University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC)  * Master of Engineering in Software Engineering	Chengdu, China Aug. 2016 – Sep. 2016
Southwest University for Nationalities (SWUN)  Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science; GPA: 3.74/4.0; Top 1 Student	Chengdu, China Sep. 2012 – Jul. 2016
• First Middle School of Zhijiang • Senior Middle School; With university entrance examination (Gaokao)	Huaihua, China Mar. 2010 – Jul. 2012
Changsha Foreign Language School Senior Middle School	Changsha, China Aug. 2009 – Feb. 2010
Second Middle School of Zhijiang  Junior Middle School	Huaihua, China Sep.2006 – Jul.2009
• Chengnan Primary School of Zhijiang • Primary School	Huaihua, China Sep. 2000 – Jul. 2006

#### Publications

- Changkun Ou, Yifei Zhan, Yaxi Chen. *Identifying Malicious Players in GWAP-based Disaster Monitoring Crowdsourcing System*. In IEEE ICAIBD' 19: Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Big Data. Chengdu, Sichuan, China, May 25-28, 2019.
- Changkun Ou, Jingyi Li, Yong Ma. Cultivation and Incentivization of HCI Research and Community in China: Taxonomy and Social Endorsements. In CHI'19 Workshop on "HCI in China: Research Agenda, Education Curriculum, Industry Partnership, and Communities Building", Glasgow, UK, May 2019, 2019.
- Changkun Ou, Malin Eiband(advisor), Daniel Buschek(co-advisor), Heinrich Hußmann(responsible professor). Understanding and Predicting Web Browsing Behavior. 2019, Master Thesis.
- Changkun Ou. An Introduction to Recent Mobile Affective Inference Techniques: Methods, Applications and Challenges. In Advanced Seminar Media Computer Science, IFI LMU, 2018. English, Slides.

- Matthias Geiger, Changkun Ou, Cedric Quintes. WatchOut: A Road Safety Extension for Pedestrians on a Public Windshield Display. In Lercture Advanced Topics in HCI, IFI LMU, 2017. English.
- Changkun Ou, Yaxi Chen(responsible professor), Andreas Butz(co-reviwer). Designing Alternative Contact-free Control Modalities for Smart Watches. 2016, Bachelor Thesis. Simplified Chinese, English
- Yaxi Chen, Changkun Ou. Combining Touch Biometrics and Motion Sensors for Hand Posture Recognition and User Authentication System. In Journal of Southwest University for Nationalities (Nature Science Edition). 2016, 42(4):429-435. Simplified Chinese
- Yaxi Chen, Changkun Ou, Zhaoyang Guo. Space interactions based on monocular vision and simple gestures. In Journal of Southwest University for Nationalities (Natural Science Edition). 2014, 40(16):871-876. Simplified Chinese
- Changkun Ou, Mu Huang, Mengxin Shi, Jiang Cheng. A Study in Keep-Right-Except-To-Pass Rule. In The Mathematical Contest in Modeling, 2014, Meritorious Winner English

## Open Talks

- Changkun Ou. A Glimpse to the Advances of Mesh Representation Learning. Internal Doctoral Colloquium Spring 2019 English.
- Changkun Ou. Understanding and Predicting User Browsing Behavior. Masters Defence Presentation, 2019 English.
- Changkun Ou. On the development of Quantified UX Metric. Design Workshop II, IFI LMU, 2018 English.
- Changkun Ou. Capsule Network with Routing Mechanism. Advanced Seminar Deep Learning, IFI LMU, 2018 Part 1, Part 2.
- Changkun Ou. *Understanding Generalization in Deep Learning*. Advanced Seminar Deep Learning, IFI LMU, 2018. English, Video.
- Hermann Redich, Patrick Börzel, Isabella Galter, Collin Leiber, Changkun Ou Convolutional Neural Networks from Zero to Hero. Advanced Seminar Deep Learning, IFI LMU, 2018. English.
- Changkun Ou. Mathematical Modelling Tutorial (Mandarin Chinese). 2016, YouTube Playlist

#### Work Experiences

Academic tutor

Munich, Germany

LMU Lecture "Machine Learning" and "Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence"

Aprl. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- o SoSe 2018, materials and notes: Homepage
- WiSe 2018/19, materials and notes: Homepage

LabEx

Chengdu, China

Vice President of Software Engineering (Remote)

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2018

• Backend: Infrastructure architecting and development: multi-cloud automation, remote desktop protocols, auto scaling, microservices

MagicLingua

Munich, Germany

Fullstack Engineer (Freelance)

Nov. 2017 – Mar. 2018

- Speech recognition: Neural network squeezing; Audio streaming solutions
- o Language Processing: Conversation understanding; Language level, modelling; Answers fault-tolerance
- $\circ$  Web development: Angular; Spring; WebSocket; MongoDB; Elasticsearch; Serverless

Shiyanlou

Software Engineer (Intern)

Chengdu, China

 $Jun. \ 2016 - Sep. \ 2016$ 

• Recommendation System: Online course recommendation system; Python; MongoDB; Collaborate Filtering

- o Distributed Log System: Elasticsearch; Logstash; Kibana; Redis
- Cross Platform Desktop Client: Electron based development for macOS/Windows/Linux
- Teaching Meterial Writing: Modern C++ based teaching meterial writing

Academic Tutor
Chengdu, China

SWUN Lecture "Human-Computer Interaction"

# Jul. 2015

#### Skills

- Languages: go; python; javascript (typescript); c/c++ (for optimization); markdown; LATEX; native Chinese; fluent professional English; elementary German
- Systems/Tools: General Linux DevOps; Docker; AWS/AlibabaCloud; MySQL/MongoDB/Redis
- Frameworks: sklearn/tensorflow/keras/opencv/numpy/matplotlib, flask, vue/angular/electron/jquery, node/express, beego/gin-gonic
- Experienced Fields:
  - **Human side**: User behavior modeling; User study; Ubiquitous interaction techniques; Quantified user experience; Website prototyping; Crowdsourcing strategy
  - Machine side: Statistical learning theory (specialize in generalization); Computer vision (specialize in convolutional network); Computer networks (specialize in transport layer protocols); Nature language processing (specialize in recurrent network methods); Distributed computing (specialize in microservices and consensus protocols)
  - o Mathematics: Stochastic process; Probability; Elementary number theory; Formal logic and proof
- Certificates: Coursera, Andrew Ng: Deep Learning Specializations, certificates: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5

## **Open Source Projects**

- Go under the hood: a book for source code study of programming language Go
- Modern C++ Tutorial: a book provides the fastest guide towards modern C++
- gomat: a matrix package with cache-aware lock-free tiling optimization in Go
- sched: a high performance reliable task scheduling package in Go
- Tensorflow docs translation: major contributor and project maintainer
- Juejin Translation Public Community: major contributor
- GitHub for more: github.com/changkun

#### Public Activities

•	Presenter	Glasgow, UK
	at The ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems	May. 2019
•	Student Volunteer at Conference Smart Graphics 2015	Chengdu, China <i>Aug. 2015</i>
•	Guigu Lab Team Leader $at SWUN$	Chengdu, China Sep. 2014 – Jun. 2015

Mathematical Modeling Association Academic Vice Director

at SWUN

Chengdu, China
Oct. 2012 – Jun. 2014

#### Honors & Awards

Siemens AILab Hackathon Munich, Germany 2nd Winner Nov. 2017 Chengdu, China China National Scholarship at UESTC Sep. 2016 **Excellent Bachelor Graduation Thesis Award** Chengdu, China at SWUN Jun. 2016 Outstanding University Graduates Student Award Chengdu, China at Sichuan Province Jan. 2016 **Outstanding Student Scholarship** Chengdu, China at SWUN Nov. 2015 Student Innovative Annual Excellent Project Chengdu, China at SWUN Jun. 2015 Chengdu, China Sichuan Province Computer Production Competition 2nd Award May 2015 China National Scholarship Chengdu, China at SWUN Sep. 2014 American Mathematical Contest in Modeling(MCM) 2014 Chengdu, China Meritorious Winner Apr. 2014

#### Personal Interests

- Open source contributions: Writting open source book; Contributing and maintaining open source softwares
- Video blogging: Making videos on YouTube channel
- Blogging and knowledge sharing: on https://changkun.de
- Video gaming: Sony Playstation and Nintendo Switch player

## References

- Prof. Andreas Butz: currently supervise for Master studies at LMU Munich Medieninformatik, Munich, Germany
- Prof. Heinrich Hußmann: exchange student course "Human-Computer Interaction I" at Southwest University for Nationalities, Chengdu, China
- Dr. Daniel Buschek: currently supervise for Master thesis at LMU Munich Medieninformatik, Munich, Germany
- Malin Eiband: currently supervise for Master thesis at LMU Munich Medieninformatik, Munich, Germany
- Florian Lachner: supervised for individual practical course at LMU Munich Medieninformatik, Munich, Germany
- Prof. Yaxi Chen: supervised for bachelor thesis at Southwest University for Nationalities, Chengdu, China
- Prof. Wei Zhou: supervised for bachelor thesis at Southwest University for Nationalities, Chengdu, China